APRIL COPES

Fullstack JavaScript Developer

OVERVIEW

Hi. My name is April. Prior to pursuing a career in software development, I was an industrial electrician specializing in PLC automation and conveyor installations. Since then, I have gained vast experience with full-stack JavaScript development, frameworks, and technologies. I am open to opportunities where I can contribute my knowledge and understanding into an organization in need of skilled, dedicated and goal oriented individuals.

SKILLS /EXPERTISE

SOL Arduino JavaScript Node.js Git / Github **jQuery** HTML5 AJAX Communication CSS3 RESTful API Perseverance React **Express** Critical Thinking Redux **JSON** Enthusiasm PostgreSQL Python

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FULLSTACK JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER WILKERSON CONVEYOR INSTALLATIONS

(JAN 2019 - Present)

- Develops full-stack JavaScript applications for privately owned conveyor installations company
- Works with CEO and team to develop strategies to lower company overhead cost
- Integrates software to influence ease in owner/employee communication, cohesion, and growth

INDUSTRIAL ELECTRICAL SUPERVISOR WILKERSON CONVEYOR INSTALLATIONS

(JUL 2016 - OCT 2018)

- Learned to orchestrate and effectively lead a team of industrial electricians to implement critical changes to existing electrical conveyor systems
- Advanced understanding of electrical schematics, PLC's, and I/O circuitry
- Oversaw the completion of critical system upgrades for projects with budgets ranging from \$10,000 to \$150,000+ throughout the country

MUSIC INSTRUCTOR

ROCKTEC MUSIC

(FEB 2013 - MAY 2016)

- Lead instructor teaching bass, acoustic and electric guitar
- Instructed children and adults of all skill levels
- Strong influences in blues, hard rock, metal, bluegrass, and classical

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

- Provides free software development training, tutoring, and mentorship to citizens in local communities
- Formulated a business structure that utilizes in-demand software/tech skills, to implement self-funded charities in underserved communities

EDUCATION

DIGITAL CRAFTS | STUDENT

16 WEEK FULLSTACK IMMERSIVE SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM

(SEP 2018 - JAN 2019)

Experience developing full stack JavaScript applications using MEAN / MERN stack

Experience debugging advanced JavaScript apps and developing clean code using agile methodology

WILKERSON ELECTRICAL CONVEYOR INSTALLATIONS APPRENTICESHIP TRAINING

ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

(JULY 2015 - AUG 2016)

- Studied how to interpret advanced electrical schematics and electrical engineering theory
- Gained experience making changes and upgrades to intricate electrical systems while complying with code and industry standards

FEATURED PROJECTS

The Pseudo Secure Initiative | https://github.com/antdevelopment1/finalCap

- Arduino, C++, JavaScript, Node.js, PostgreSQL, Express, HTML, CSS, Twilio, Bcrypt
- Fullstack Security System App utilizing an Ultrasonic Sensor to detect an intruder's approx. distance and airwave interference.

Yum World | https://github.com/antdevelopment1/reactFoodApp

- HTML, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript, React, React Router
- React web app that allows the user to select a dish from around the world. This app uses a recipe API.